<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Plane on Holistic Security</title>
    <link>https://holisticsecurity.io/tags/data-plane/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Plane on Holistic Security</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holisticsecurity.io/tags/data-plane/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building your own affordable K8s to host a Service Mesh - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://holisticsecurity.io/2020/01/16/building-your-own-affordable-cloud-k8s-to-host-a-service-mesh-data-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holisticsecurity.io/2020/01/16/building-your-own-affordable-cloud-k8s-to-host-a-service-mesh-data-plane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to build a Container-based Cloud to deploy any kind of workload (RESTful API, Microservices, Event-Driven, Functions, etc.) but it should be affordable, ready to use, reliable, secure and productionable. This means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Productionable: should be fully functional and ready to be used as a production environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliable and Secure: able to improve the security level by implementing more security controls, at least fully isolated secure private networking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affordable: cheaper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ready to use: able to be automated (DevOps and IaC) with a mature management API.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below a high level architecture of Container-based Cloud I want to get. I will focus on the Service Mesh Data Plane.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://holisticsecurity.io/assets/img/20200116-service-mesh-01-reference-arch-2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://holisticsecurity.io/assets/img/20200116-service-mesh-01-reference-arch-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Service Mesh hosted in a Container-based Cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These requeriments restric some options, all of them using any Public Cloud Provider, but considering the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/spot&#34;&gt;AWS Spot Instances&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/preemptible-vms&#34;&gt;Google Cloud Preemptible VM Instances&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately Microsoft Azure only provides Low-Priority VMs to be used from Azure Batch Service. But if you are new user, you could apply for using the Free Tier in all of 3 Cloud Providers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
