<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ingress on Holistic Security</title>
    <link>https://holisticsecurity.io/tags/ingress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ingress on Holistic Security</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://holisticsecurity.io/tags/ingress/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sidecar Proxy: The Security Building Block</title>
      <link>https://holisticsecurity.io/2020/05/13/sidecar-proxy-the-security-building-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holisticsecurity.io/2020/05/13/sidecar-proxy-the-security-building-block/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as a HTTP reverse proxy is sitting in front of a web application and a sidecar is attached to a motorcycle; a sidecar proxy is attached to a main application to extend or add functionality. A Sidecar Proxy is an application design pattern which abstracts certain features, such as inter-service communications, monitoring and &lt;strong&gt;security&lt;/strong&gt;, away from the main application to ease its maintainability, resilience and scalability of the application as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I will show you how to use the Sidecar Pattern to address security challenges in the Cloud Native Applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://holisticsecurity.io/assets/blog20200513_sidecar/proxy-pattern-reverse-api-gateway-lb-sidecar-1-evolution.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building your own affordable K8s to host a Service Mesh - Part 2: External DNS and Ingress</title>
      <link>https://holisticsecurity.io/2020/01/22/building-your-own-affordable-cloud-k8s-to-host-a-service-mesh-part2-external-dns-ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://holisticsecurity.io/2020/01/22/building-your-own-affordable-cloud-k8s-to-host-a-service-mesh-part2-external-dns-ingress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to get an affordable Kubernetes, every part we&amp;rsquo;re going to use should be affordable too, and ones of the expensive and tricky things are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing&#34;&gt;AWS Elastic Load Balancing (ELB)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/route53&#34;&gt;AWS Route 53 (DNS)&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately, Kubernetes SIGs are working to address this gap with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/external-dns&#34;&gt;Kubernetes ExternalDNS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what is the problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart of it is expensive, the problem is every time I deploy a &lt;code&gt;Service&lt;/code&gt; in Kubernetes I have to update and add a new DNS entry in the Cloud Provider&amp;rsquo;s DNS manually. Yes, of course, the process can be automated, but the idea is doing it during the provisioning time. In other words, every developer can publish theirs services adding the DNS name as annotation for that services can be called over Internet.
Yes, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/dns&#34;&gt;Kubernetes brings by default a DNS&lt;/a&gt; but this is an internal one and it is only to work resolving DNS names over the Kubernetes Network, not for internet facing services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kubernetes ExternalDNS will run a program in our affordable K8s which it will synchronize exposed Kubernetes Services and Ingresses with the Cloud Provider&amp;rsquo;s DNS Service, in this case with AWS Route 53. Below you can view a high level diagram and current status of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://holisticsecurity.io/2020/01/16/building-your-own-affordable-cloud-k8s-to-host-a-service-mesh-data-plane&#34;&gt;Affordable Kubernetes Data Plane, I recommend look at first post about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://holisticsecurity.io/assets/img/20200122-service-mesh-01-affordablek8s-aws-arch.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://holisticsecurity.io/assets/img/20200122-service-mesh-01-affordablek8s-aws-arch.png&#34; alt=&#34;Service Mesh hosted using AWS Spot Instances&#34; title=&#34;Service Mesh using AWS Spot Instances&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
